Yuanyuan (Lilian) Sun

Summary------

Highly motivated grad student in computer science & award-winning backend software developer with 5+ years of experience. Extensive background in full software development lifecycle including design, coding, testing, debugging, maintenance of web applications. Proficiency in OOP, Data Preparation, Data Processing. Fast-learning Ability.

Education-----

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL, USA M.S. in Computer Science (GPA 3.66/4.0) Dec. 2023 Suzhou University of Science and Technology, Suzhou, China B.S. in Computer Science and Technology Jun. 2016

Tech Skills-----

Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Apache Maven, Mybatis, JMeter | Python, Flask | SQL, NoSQL(Redis, MongoDB) | JavaScript, HTML, CSS | AWS Cloud Services, Docker, Linux command, Git | Tomcat/Weblogic Server | Agile Software Development Methodologies (e.g. scrum) | R programming

Experience------

Senior Software Engineer Mar. 2019 - Dec. 2021 Shanghai Highly Electric Co., Ltd Shanghai, China

- Provided estimates for web application design, development, testing. Selected appropriate libraries and open-source technologies for project integration.
- ➤ Designed a scalable service architecture and re-architected old & complex applications by applying a unifying framework, improved operational efficiency, reliability, adaptability. Reduced user complaints by 65% and reduced the cost of operation & maintenance by 15% between 2020 and 2021.
- Analyzed, designed, implemented reusable, scalable APIs, system agnostic, and global are critical, supported building, and deployment of new products and features.
- ➤ Tested software for bugs and operating speed, designed and implemented stress tests on high-concurrency interfaces. Fixing bugs and documenting processes to increase efficiency by 20% from 2019-2021 on three projects, two platforms.
- > Oversaw full lifecycle of software development for 3 projects with on-time delivery while staying 5% under budget.
- Mentor the junior developers & 2 summer interns

Junior Software Developer Mar. 2017 - Mar. 2019 Shanghai Mathartsys Co., Ltd Shanghai, China

- Analyzed user requirements, and designed functional and flexible web services by UML, created detailed design documentation, unit test plans, and well-documented code.
- ➤ Built RESTful APIs that served data to the JavaScript front-end based on Java, J2EE, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Mybatis, SQL, etc. technologies.
- Maintained 11 enterprise web applications and enhanced the automated build and deploy process for applications.
- Researched and evaluated methods and techniques to solve problems and reduce friction in development lifecycle, documenting and presenting reports to leadership twice a month.
- Revamped web application, security applications, minimizing hacker attacks from 33.3% to 3.2%.

Major Projects-----

- ♦ Customer Segmentation
- ♦ Compressor Selection System based on Linear Regression
- ♦ Intelligent Logistics Shortest Path Optimization System
- ♦ SAIC-GM Automobile After-sales Platform